<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-07-22T10:56:50+00:00</updated><id>https://tim-forrer.github.io//feed.xml</id><title type="html">tim forrer</title><subtitle>My personal website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Working from ‘Home’</title><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2023/working-from-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working from ‘Home’"/><published>2023-04-15T06:18:20+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T06:18:20+00:00</updated><id>https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2023/working-from-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2023/working-from-home/"><![CDATA[<p>I spent the week in Kyoto, and am beginning to pick up a new language.</p> <hr/> <p>Last week I was ‘WFH’ in Kyoto, and gotta say it seemed much more fun than last time we went, despite not really doing as much. Might have been helped by the fact that the hotel we stayed at was actually quite nice, with this new kind of shower that had jets that sprayed water horizontally at your body - was a lot of fun!</p> <p>Also there is a crazy amount of noodle based shops in Kyoto, I never realised before. I think it’s reinforced to me that I’m definite a rice guy than a noodle guy - definitely had huge cravings by the end.</p> <p>That being said I think if I was going to pick somewhere else to live in Japan outside of Tokyo, I think it would be Kyoto (even over Osaka which is definitely the more fun place). For some reason I just prefer the general vibes of the place. Can’t quite put my finger on it.</p> <p>Also got to see some deer in Nara! Rui Lan said that they bow to you if you bow to them, like Hippogriffs in Harry Potter. I thought that there was no way that would be true, but actually, it really happens (sometimes). That was right up there with the most Japan things I’ve seen here.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/deer.jpg" alt="deer" width="100%"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update,"/><category term="general"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I spent the week in Kyoto, and am beginning to pick up a new language.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">春合宿（Spring Camp)</title><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2023/post-camp-thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="春合宿（Spring Camp)"/><published>2023-03-19T09:42:20+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-19T09:42:20+00:00</updated><id>https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2023/post-camp-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2023/post-camp-thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p>I finally saw a monkey!</p> <hr/> <p>Just the one though :(</p> <p>Went with the badminton club to a spring training camp in 群馬(Gunma), which was about 2.5 hours drive north of Tokyo. Tbh I was a bit unsure about how it might be, especially since we had been randomly drawn into rooms of 3 and Shimada scared me. Rui Lan said I should take it as a chance to get to know him better, and maybe he wouldn’t be so scary afterwards - which kinda worked out, in that he’s not <em>as</em> scary as before (but I’m still not sure I’d chose to be in a room with him).</p> <p>Whilst I didn’t necessarily become closer to people I wasn’t already friendly with, the people who I was friendly with I think it was good in that spending this kind of time together (I was going to say ‘outside of training’ but that wouldn’t necessarily be very accurate, given that we were training all day from 9-5), they see me less as an older PhD student and more as someone who also enjoys playing badminton, so it was definitely time well spent.</p> <p>I also had the joy of a conference submission deadline coincide with this camp but thankfully I was able to get most of it done it advance, and what I couldn’t I had the great help of my co-authors to finish off for me - one of whom is also somehow managing to finish his PhD thesis at the same time as guiding me through the quagmire that is categorical quantum mechanics. Fingers crossed that we’ll get a submission approved.</p> <p>Anyways, as can be inferred from the recent lack of activity, I think I’ll keep posts a bit shorter from now on, given that the PhD life is really starting to hit hard now.</p> <p>Only thing left to say is that I’m so sad I didn’t try harder to get a good picture of the monkey… Here’s the photo I did get anyways.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/monkeys.jpg" alt="monkeys" width="100%"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update,"/><category term="general"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I finally saw a monkey!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Belated Birthday Post</title><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/belated-birthday/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Belated Birthday Post"/><published>2022-11-20T16:13:20+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-20T16:13:20+00:00</updated><id>https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/belated-birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/belated-birthday/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m 24 now. How delightful. I’m sure you will be suitably cheered by this one, as I actually was, believe it or not.<br/> Not about COP or WC2022 I mean - my birthday.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="good-cop-bad-cop">Good COP, Bad COP?</h2> <p>(No-one’s <em>ever</em> used that before)</p> <p>COP ended yesterday with triumphant scenes but I can’t help but feel we’ve seen this all before.<br/> I try to live in hope that perhaps things really will change - but Yoda always said there is no try so I’ll leave it up to you to decide if I’m ‘do-ing’ or ‘do not-ing’.</p> <h2 id="we-dont-care-2022">W(e don’t) C(are) 2022</h2> <p>Yes that incrediblely well thought out title was a reference to the Qatar WC, which kicked off today.<br/> Another marker of corporate greed trampling over moral decency for when aliens come to establish the history of a long lost ancient civilasation known as humankind in thousands of years to come.<br/> Could well be 10 years at this rate though.</p> <p>What unsettles me is not just</p> <ul> <li>the awarding of the WC to a corrupt, homophobic nation intent on sportswashing its image,</li> <li>or the conditions under which immigrant workers suffered and died so that the necessary infrastructure could be built,</li> <li>or how the rights of LGBTQ+ people are being tossed aside to line Infantino’s pockets (don’t worry though he feels gay because he was once ginger),</li> </ul> <p>but also the blatent disregard for the very spectacle itself with footballers dropping out like flies.</p> <p>What, actually, is the point of the whole thing?<br/> (I have a slightly cynical answer which again, I’ll leave to your imagination.)</p> <p>What I found most bizarre though is the amount of press coverage that the last minute ban of beer inside stadiums recieved.</p> <p>Perhaps as someone who doesn’t drink I’m poorly positioned to comment, but I hardly found that to be the breaking news story that some outlets reported it to be - although in truth I would like to read some official statement containing the mental gymnastics that is being performed in justifying its continued sale in corporate areas.</p> <h2 id="so-another-politics-thing-happened">So another politics thing happened</h2> <p>Jeremy Hunt also unveiled his Autumn Statement but I’ve not bothered to read it so it’s hardly fair of me to comment on it. I did also write before about the lunacy of allowing Truss and co. to have such a profound impact on the UK economy so if Jeremy Huny has indeed undone all of it then I suppose I should be happy about that.</p> <h2 id="happy-times">Happy Tim(es)</h2> <p>What I am happy about is my birthday, which was the 24th such commemoration of my entering the world, and which I must say was certainly up there amongst the greats.<br/> For this I owe a great deal of thanks to Rui Lan, who some how managed to message about 20 people she’d never met before to help me celebrate - most of whom she had to message in Japanese. To be honest prior to that I never really felt like I had people whom I could call actual friends here.</p> <p>The problem is every one is too damn nice!<br/> (Trust me to find a complaint about any and everything…)</p> <p>But it makes it hard to tell when people are being nice to you because they want to become friends, or if they are doing so out of social politeness and actually would rather I left them alone. That’s a bit pot calling kettle coming from me though.</p> <p>After the many things that we did together though, I did feel like I had a better idea of who I could really call a friend.<br/> But even moreso had a better idea of how amazing Rui Lan actually is, and how lucky I am that she not only tolerates such a moody git, but would go to such difficulty to organise something like that for one.</p> <h2 id="a-return-to-your-normal-ranting-programme">A return to your normal ranting programme</h2> <p>Finally, Twitter was also bought on my birthday which I’m rather neutral about overall, and I’m sure the buyer wishes he could return.</p> <p>Yes it is amusing watching Elon Musk speedrun any% a huge social network to the ground but similarly, he’s chucking away <span>$</span>44 billion on ‘freeing the bird’ - when Pakistan suffered an estimated damages of <span>$</span>40 billion after floods that have set the backdrop to this year’s edition of COP, and after the promise of giving Indonesia $20 billion to transition away from coal was widely celebrated as a huge achivement.</p> <p>I wonder how many things would have constituted a better investment of that $44 billion, than stacking it all up, setting a blue bird atop of it, and setting in on fire for Bonfire night?</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/fireworks.jpg" alt="fireworks-from-skytree" width="100%"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update,"/><category term="general"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m 24 now. How delightful. I’m sure you will be suitably cheered by this one, as I actually was, believe it or not. Not about COP or WC2022 I mean - my birthday.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Changes Large and Small</title><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/small-steps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Changes Large and Small"/><published>2022-10-23T02:22:20+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-23T02:22:20+00:00</updated><id>https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/small-steps</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/small-steps/"><![CDATA[<p>I finish my Ranking War, the UK PM resigns (again) and one of Bozo’s Jokers gets engaged.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="small-changes-for-me">Small Changes for Me</h2> <p>So my ランク戦 (Ranking War) finished on Monday. On the whole it was markedly more successful than last time around (I got zero wins and my freefall was only halted by the withdrawal of an opponent due to injury).</p> <p>Managed to pick up two wins in my group of four, both over players who I’d struggled against in the past so that was a good sign of progress, placing me in second place in the group.</p> <p>Since the person who topped our group won against the bottom ranked player from the group above, I still had a chance to keep climbing provided I too beat the bottom ranked player from the group above. Sadly despite taking the first game (the first time I’d ever taken a game off this player), I wasn’t able to take another and lost 1-2.</p> <p>Anyways now that that’s over I can focus fully on (another) reconstruction of my swing. I finally plucked up the courage to ask 清水さん (one of the coaches) about my overhead swing and he explained a few things that I could do differently. I felt a bit bad since this perhaps took a lot longer than he might have expected given the language barrier but I think we got there in the end.</p> <p>One of the two areas he told me to change was to switch to a style of footwork that encouraged greater balance. I suppose right about now a more sage blogger than I would make some smooth comment about how this reflected a change that they could also make in their day-to-day life.<br/> But I am no such blogger so we move swiftly on.</p> <h2 id="large-changes-for-the-uk">Large Changes for the UK</h2> <p>Liz Truss’ reign as PM has finally ended after 45 days in office - not quite the new ‘era’ that I dubbed it in my previous post…</p> <p>I find it incredible how badly it all went wrong for her, especially given that about two weeks was taken up entirely by the death of the Queen. One of the only positives to have come out of this entire shambles was this image from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Championship/comments/y99azv/number_of_watford_managers_per_prime_minister/">/u/Bumfuddlediddled</a>, displaying the number of Watford Managers per Prime Minister.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/watfordmanagers_pm.WEBP" alt="watford-managers-per-pm" width="100%"/></p> <p>And lettuce never forget (sorry) that she was not in the end able to outlast the lettuce.</p> <p>But beyond the jokes and silly stats, it really is incredible how much damage this government has done in such a short time to the UK and its people. The constant U-turns, massive economic upheaval and even scandals that occurred in this short time is beyond belief. And now there’s even real talk of bringing Boris Johnson back, after everything that happened during his time. It’s absolutely shocking and the sooner the public have a real say with a general election, the better.<br/> No wonder Armando Ianucci said it would be impossible to bring back The Thick of It.</p> <p>It’s also 100 years of the BBC apparently, and this anniversary brought this video to light, where Guy Goma, a prospective interviewee for a job at the BBC, was mistaken for the technology journalist Guy <em>Kewney</em> to discuss <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Corps_v_Apple_Computer">Apple Corps v Apple Computer</a>.<br/> (Sadly he never got the job.)</p> <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e6Y2uQn_wvc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> <h2 id="massive-changes-for-zac-and-kirsty">Massive Changes for Zac and Kirsty</h2> <p>Finally and most importantly, the first member of Bozo’s Jokers (our LoL team from secondary school) got engaged recently!</p> <p>I hope that you and Kirsty have every happiness in your life together.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update,"/><category term="general"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I finish my Ranking War, the UK PM resigns (again) and one of Bozo’s Jokers gets engaged.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New eras</title><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/a-new-era/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New eras"/><published>2022-09-28T03:38:20+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-28T03:38:20+00:00</updated><id>https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/a-new-era</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/a-new-era/"><![CDATA[<p>Well, I certainly picked an interesting day to write my first post.<br/> I doubt today will be quite as exciting.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="new-monarch">New monarch</h2> <p>I certainly didn’t imagine the death of Queen Elizabeth II would have such an impact on me as it did. Not in the sense that I feel a great loss, but in the sense of the magnitude of change that people in the UK will be experiencing now. In some sense it marks a sort of loss of identity for myself. Having been away from home during such a seismic event, I sort of feel this is a real milestone in my departure from experiencing life through the lens of a ‘British’ person. Instead of experiencing this event, I observed it from afar, as every other person outside of the UK has done, and now I feel a separation between myself and the ‘general British consciousness’, whatever that might mean.</p> <p>I’ve always said I never really felt like a British person, and that feeling (naturally) seems to be getting ever more acute.</p> <h2 id="new-prime-minister">New prime minister</h2> <p>And the new eras don’t stop there this September.</p> <p>The UK in addition to a new monarch also got a new PM in Liz Truss, who recieved a whopping(!) 81,326 votes to win the Tory leadership election. I don’t have much of a clue about politics beyond a sound-bite here or there I’ll be the first to admit, but I find it crazy that the next PM can be decided by such a small minority of the UK public, it doesn’t seem to really be in keeping with the democratic nature of our politics.</p> <p>Whilst I doubt that many would vote for their constituencies majority favourite, I do feel like it should have been left up to the conservative MPs to decide the new leader, since at least they have been voted to represent a larger base of UK voters. But whatever, fine, ok, maybe it’s not in keeping with the rules of the 1922 committee or some other group to do that.</p> <p>Surely though being elected as PM in such a fashion, with such a small minority of votes, it cannot then be possible to bring in such mega sweeping changes to the UK economy in a ‘mini’-budget?</p> <p>It just seems absurd to me.</p> <p>Again, I’ll be the first to admit I’m no economic expert (maybe I should stop really commenting on things I’m no expert on…), but it seems blatently obvious to me that measures such as the abolition of the 45% higher rate of income tax will only serve to help those who are more well off. And surely such a seismic shift should be accompanied by a forecast by an independent body, especially in light of the fact that there is so little electoral support for the current government?</p> <p>Clearly not it would seem.<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p> <p>So, now if an massive international agency of the UN tells you that they would ‘not recommend large and untargeted fiscal packages’ and that ‘the nature of the UK measures will likely increase inequality’,<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> will such an undemocratically elected government then take time to re-evaluate its approach?</p> <p>I would hope so but I do not hold my breath.</p> <h2 id="new-coach">New coach</h2> <p>In perhaps what was unsurprisingly not the biggest news story on the day of the Queen’s death, Chelsea head coach Thomas Tuchel was sacked and replaced by the now former Brighton and Hove Albion manager, Graham Potter.</p> <p>I’m in two minds personally about this change. I think Thomas Tuchel did deserve better. He led us to a Champion’s League trophy and steadied the ship during a tumultuous (to say the least) second half of the season, including two other finals that technically we didn’t lose (didn’t really do much to try and win though either). But I didn’t believe that he was really the right person to lead Chelsea through the ‘long term project’ that so many of us fans desire. His style of football was never overly inspirational nor entertaining, even if he did get wins, and I think during the rough patches there really wasn’t anything much to cheer about. For a long term project, I think you have to keep the fans entertained at the very least so that they keep the faith through trying times. So maybe this was the right decision for the future of the club if a long term project is what we really want.</p> <p>Although I’ll be the first to admit… well, you get the idea by now.</p> <p>In truth the person I feel most sorry for is Billy Gilmour - sold to BHFC to get gametime under a coach renowned for developing talent, only to have that coach move to the very club who just sold you 7 days later.</p> <p>In any case, I’m looking forward in incoming influx of Harry Potter jokes on Reddit, and I’m hoping that we’ll be able to look back on the Graham Potter era fondly and say:</p> <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpRIetBN5UI?start=43" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> <h2 id="other-bits-and-bobs">Other bits and bobs</h2> <p>It was Shinzo Abe’s state funeral yesterday and there was a marked increase in police presence on our walk into Shibuya yesterday evening which was interesting. I guess that the route his urn was taking might have been due to follow the same roads that we were walking along.</p> <p>Anyway I tried to get a few pictures and managed one that I was reasonably happy with. Sadly I didn’t get the focus right, but I was rushing because I’m not really sure what the protocol is when taking photos on such an occasion. I’m sure it’s probably fine to take photos of the police, but then again my mum always did drive into me a deep fear of authority.</p> <p>Til the next.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/\1{:width=&quot;100%&quot;}{:width=&quot;100%&quot;}" alt="police_at_hanamasa_bridge" width="100%"/></p> <div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <ol> <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote"> <p>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-62970803 <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote"> <p>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-63051702 <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> </ol> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update,"/><category term="general"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, I certainly picked an interesting day to write my first post. I doubt today will be quite as exciting.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World"/><published>2022-09-08T03:58:20+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-08T03:58:20+00:00</updated><id>https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tim-forrer.github.io//blog/2022/hello-world/"><![CDATA[<p>As I approach the one year mark of being in Japan, and with the start of my doctoral programme looming, I thought that it might be a good time to further inflict my presence on the world.</p> <hr/> <p>This website has been purposed as a blogging website purely because Github pages is free and this seems to be the easiest way to setup a website on here. Sometimes I think it would be fun to write a blog but honestly I’m not sure I have enough content going on in my life, nor enough interesting thoughts to really merit it.</p> <p>So what is this website then? Well mainly I’ve made it because every researcher seems to have their own website so it seems silly not to have one also. I’ve found that not treading the path oft-walked leads to getting mauled by a bear.</p> <p>I also often come across personally useful things, like programming tricks or somesuch, that are buried deep on the interwebs, or just on websites with too much other content to make it easy to scroll through and find (for SEO or something I guess). So I’ll probably post those kinds of things from time to time just to make my life easier when trying to find stuff again.</p> <p>The final purpose of this website is for people who I’ve (in some sense) left behind in the UK. It would do them a great injustice I think to say that no-one cares about what’s going on in my day-to-day life. And I write that with no sense of ego, but in fact immense gratitude to have such great friends. As time goes by I find it’s becoming increasingly difficult to find time to catchup and chat. I often find myself thinking that perhaps I could, and should, be making a greater effort towards reciprocating the efforts that other’s have made towards me. So I hope that for them, this does serve as some kind of effort. And I’d like them to know how grateful I am to still be able to count upon them, no matter how many miles might separate us.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I approach the one year mark of being in Japan, and with the start of my doctoral programme looming, I thought that it might be a good time to further inflict my presence on the world.]]></summary></entry></feed>